(ROARING)
(SWORDS CLANGING)
(WAR CRIES)
MAN: Fall back!
(WIND HOWLING)
(PANTING)
Brother?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SAMWELL SCREAMS)
(GHOST GROWLING)
(WHIMPERING)
(PANTING)
Did you send the ravens?
Tarty. look at me.
That was your job.
Your only job.
We need to get back to the Wall.
It's a long march.
We know what's out there.
but we have to make it. have to warn them
or before winter's done.
everyone you've ever known will be dead.
(WIND HOWLING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
First time you've seen a giant. Jon Snow?
(EXHALES)
Well. don't stare too long. They're shy.
When they stop being shy. they get angry.
And when they're angry.
I've seen them pound a man
straight into the ground
like a hammer on a nail.
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
-MAN 1: Crow!
-BOY 1: Crow!
GIRL 1: Look over there!
MAN 2: Crow!
GIRL 2: Crow! Look over here! Look!
WOMAN: Look. crow coming!
BOY 2: Crow!
YGRITTE: You're wearing the wrong color.
Mance was a ranger.
(GRUNTS)
In your hearts. all you crows want to fly free.
JON: When I'm free. will I be free to go?
-Crow!
Sure. you will.
-(GROANS)
-(ALL LAUGHING)
And I'll be free to kill you.
Got no respect. this lot.
Got no fathers to slap them when they're foul.
What happened to their fathers?
Some of them were killed by crows like you.
Don't look so grim. Jon Snow.
If Mance Rayder likes you.
you'll live another day.
And if he don't...
TORMUND: I smell a crow.
We killed his friends.
Thought you'd want to question this one.
What do we want with a baby crow?
This baby killed Qhorin Half hand.
He wants to be one of us.
That half-handed cunt killed friends of mine.
Friends twice your size.
My father told me
big men fall just as quick as little ones
if you put a sword through their hearts.
Plenty of little men
tried to put their swords through my heart.
And there's plenty of little skeletons
buried in the woods.
What's your name. boy?
Jon Snow.
Your Grace.
(LAUGHING)
-Your Grace?
-(ALL LAUGHING)
Did you hear that?
From now on. you'd better
kneel every time I fart.
(CHUCKLING)
Stand. boy.
We don't kneel for anyone beyond the Wall.
So. you're Ned Stark's bastard.
Thank you for the gift.
Lord of Bones. You can leave us.
The girl likes you.
You like her back. Snow?
That why you want to join us?
TORMUND: Don't panic. boy.
This isn't the damned Night's Watch
Where we make you swear off girls.
This chicken eater you thought was
king is Tormund Giantsbane.
Can't believe this pup killed the Half hand.
MANCE: He was our enemy
and I'm glad he's dead.
He was my brother once.
Back when he had a whole hand.
What were you doing with him?
The Lord Commander
sent me to the Half hand for seasoning.
Why?
He wants me to lead one day.
But here you are. a traitor.
kneeling before the King-beyond-the-Wall.
If I'm a traitor. then you are. too.
Why do you want to join us. Jon Snow?
I want to be free.
No. I don't think so.
I think what you
want most of all is to be a hero.
I'll ask you one last time.
why do you want to join us?
We stopped at Craster's Keep
on the way north.
I saw...
You saw what?
I saw Craster take his own baby
boy and leave it in the woods.
I saw what took it.
You're telling me you saw one of them?
And why would that make you
desert your brothers?
Because when I told the Lord Commander.
he already knew.
Thousands of years ago.
the First Men defeated the White Walkers.
I want to fight for the side
that fights for the living.
Did I come to the right place?
We'll need to find you a new cloak.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
What if you took off that bit there?
(CHUCKLES) Don't you
want to leave something to the imagination?
Trouble is. I've never had much imagination.
I want you to take it off.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Mouth.
(DOOR OPENING)
PODRICK: Ser Bronn. Ser Bronn.
BRONN: I didn't hear that.
-Apologies. ser.
-BRONN: Back away.
Keep backing away
till you're outside this establishment.
Then back away some more.
Lord Tyrion sent me.
I will murder you. boy.
He said it was a matter of life and death.
(SIGHS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Pod?
CERSEI: It's your sister.
The queen.
TYRION: What are they doing here?
Protecting me. I assume. Will you let me in?
No. I don't think so.
If I wanted to kill you.
do you think I'd let a wooden door stop me?
They stay outside.
I'm not afraid of you. little brother.
(CREAKING)
Why are you here?
I wanted to see your face.
They said you'd lost your nose.
but it's not as gruesome as all that.
The man who cut me lost more than his nose.
I should hope so.
The rebels came
for Joffrey's head. they lost their own.
Thanks to Father.
Of course. it wasn't a rebel
who tried to kill me.
No? Curious.
Bit of a comedown from chamber of the Hand.
But then I don't suppose
you need much room.
Grand Maester Pycelle made the same joke.
You must be proud to be as funny as a
man whose balls brush his knees.
You're meeting Father today?
How do you know that?
Because I have
hundreds of spies in my employ.
The Master of Whisperers
owes me a favor or two.
Father told me. What do you want from him?
What do I want from him? He's my father.
Do I need to want something?
I'm sure he loves me dearly.
as any father loves his child. his baby boy.
Yet he hasn't come to visit once...
-Hmm.
-...since arriving in King's Landing.
I lay here. my face split in half.
but Father never came.
You're going to make me cry.
Why do you care what I want from him?
Because
you've slandered me to Father before.
Slandered? When?
You told him I had my guards
beat that servant girl at Casterly Rock.
You did have your
guards beat her. A girl of nine. I believe.
I was nine. too.
She lost an eye. if I remember correctly.
If I remember correctly.
she never stole a necklace again. (LAUGHS)
It's not slander if it's true.
And what's this truth
you plan on telling him today?
Why are you so nervous
about what I'm going to say to Father?
Because you're a liar.
I expect you'll
tell lies about me. about Joffrey.
Any lies in particular?
(SIGHS) You're a clever man.
but not as clever as you think you are.
Mmm. Still makes me more clever than you.
(DOOR OPENS)
Ah.
Look at these two shining warriors.
Set Taryn Mant and Set Whosit of Whocares.
Set Meryn Tram.
Ser Bronn of the Blackwater.
-You're no knight.
-Pod.
Ser Bronn of the Blackwater
was anointed by the king himself.
You're an up-jumped cutthroat. nothing more.
That's exactly who I am.
And you're a grub in fancy armor
who's better at
beating little girls than fighting men.
Now. I have an appointment with Lord Tyrion.
You put your hand on that door.
you lose the hand.
As much as I appreciate
a walk in the sunshine.
I am wondering why you sent for me.
Many people in this
city want to kill me. You're here to protect me.
I've been doing that for a while now.
Do you grow bored protecting me?
I grow poor protecting you.
Poor? Poor?
Under my patronage you've become a knight.
you've served as Commander
of the City Watch.
Briefly.
I'm sure you filled your pockets.
And now my pockets are empty.
You've given me a taste for the finer things.
And if you want me
protecting you. you'll need to pay more.
I thought we were friends.
We are.
But I'm a sell sword. I sell my sword.
I don't loan it out to friends as a favor.
-How much?
-Double.
Double?
I'm a knight now.
Knights are worth double.
I don't even know
how much I'm paying you now.
Which means you can afford it.
(SOFT GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
Here. Here!
Help me!
(EXHALES)
(SHIP HORN BLOWING)
(PANTING)
Who are you?
I was in the battle at Blackwater.
I was a captain and a knight.
Aye. ser. and serving which king?
The one true king of Westeros.
Stannis Baratheon.
I thought you were dead.
Everyone thought you were dead.
And your son?
He may have swam ashore as you did.
No. the wildfire took him. I saw it.
I'm so sorry. my friend.
I. too. have lost a son.
There is nothing worse in this world.
But. Davos. you were a good father.
If I was a good father. he'd still be here.
Stannis lives?
He licks his wounds at Dragonstone.
Will you take me there?
There is nothing for me at Dragonstone.
This war is not over.
Not for you. maybe.
But for Salladhor Seen. the war is over.
We're both sworn to King Stannis.
I am sworn to no man.
I promised you 30 ships
and you promised me riches and glory.
I delivered the ships.
Stannis never gives up. Never.
Now he will regroup...
He's a broken man.
His fleet lies at the bottom of Blackwater Bay.
They say he sees no one.
not his generals. not even his wife.
Only the Red Woman whispering in his ear.
telling him what she sees in the flames
and burning men alive.
What?
They built a great fire when Stannis returned.
All those who spoke
against her she called servants of darkness.
They say she sang to them as they burned.
I'm a pirate.
You're a smuggler. Servants of darkness.
I'm thinking Dragonstone
is a good place for us to avoid.
Take me back there. please.
(SCOFFS) You cannot turn
Stannis against her.
Maybe not. but I could carve her heart out.
You could try.
If you fail. they will burn you.
If you succeed. they'll burn you.
And you've only just come back to life.
(CHUCKLES) Stay alive
a little longer. my friend.
You call me friend.
You drank with me on my wedding day.
And you drank with me on four of mine.
but I don't ask you for favors.
I have to stop her. Please. do this for me.
When you are dead.
I will gather your bones in a little sack
and let your widow
wear them around her neck.
We should set
the siege lines 1.000 yards from Harrenhal.
There won't be a siege.
The Mountain can't defend a ruin.
The Mountain will defend
whatever Tywin Lannister tells him.
The Lannisters
have been running from us since Oxcross.
I'd love a fight. The men would love a fight.
I don't think we're going to get one.
(BLOOD DRIPPING)
(FLY BUZZING)
RICKARD: Two hundred Northmen
slaughtered like sheep.
The debt will be repaid. my friend.
For them and for your sons.
Will it?
They rot in the ground
while their killer runs free.
The Kingslayer won't remain free for long.
My best hunters are after him.
ROBB: A Mallister?
CATELYN: Ser Jeremy.
My father's bannerman.
(SIGHS)
Find her a chamber that will serve as a cell.
TALISA: She's your mother.
ROBB: She freed Jaime Lannister.
The Lannisters robbed them of their sons
and she robbed them of their justice.
(COUGHING)
QYBURN: Water.
(WHISPERS) Water.
This needs to be cleaned and closed.
What's your name. friend?
Qyburn.
You're lucky to be alive.
Lucky?
The badge looks good on you.
Almost as good as it looked on me.
Are you enjoying your new position?
Am I enjoying it?
I was very happy as Hand of the King.
(TYWIN CHUCKLES)
Yes. I heard how happy you were.
(BLOWS)
You brought a whore into my bed.
It wasn't your bed at the time.
I sent you here to advise the king.
I gave you real power and authority.
You chose to spend your days
as you always have.
bedding harlots and drinking with thieves.
Occasionally I drank with the harlots.
What do you want. Tyrion?
Why does everyone assume
I want something?
Can't I simply visit with my beloved father?
My beloved father who
somehow forgot to visit his wounded son
after he fell on the battlefield.
Maester Pycelle assured me
your wounds were not fatal.
I organized the defense of this city
While you held court in the ruins of Harrenhal.
I led the foray
when the enemies were at the gate
while your grandson.
the king. quivered in fear behind the walls.
I bled in the mud for our family.
And as my reward.
I was trundled off to some dark little cell.
But What do I want?
A little bloody gratitude would be a start.
Jugglers and singers require applause.
You are a Lannister.
Do you think I demanded a garland of roses
every time I suffered a wound on a battlefield?
Hmm?
Now. I have seven kingdoms to look after
and three of them are in open rebellion.
So tell me what you want.
I want what is mine by right.
Jaime is your eldest son.
heir to your lands and titles.
But he is a Kingsguard.
forbidden from marriage or inheritance.
The day Jaime put on the white cloak.
he gave up his claim to Casterly Rock.
I am your son and lawful heir.
You want Casterly Rock?
It is mine by right.
(SIGHS)
We'll find you accommodations
more suited to your name
and as a reward for your accomplishments
during the battle of Blackwater Bay.
And when the time is right. you will be given a
position fit for your talents
so that you can
serve your family and protect our legacy.
And if you serve faithfully.
you will be rewarded with a suitable wife.
And I would let myself
be consumed by maggots
before mocking the family
name and making you heir to Casterly Rock.
Why?
You ask that?
You. who killed your mother
to come into the world?
You are an ill-made. spiteful little creature
full of envy. lust. and low cunning.
Men's laws give you the right to bear my
name and display my colors
since I cannot prove that you are not mine.
And to teach me humility.
the Gods have condemned me
to watch you waddle about
wearing that proud lion
that was my father's sigil
and his father's before him.
But neither Gods nor men
will ever compel me to
let you turn Casterly Rock
into your whorehouse.
Go. now.
Speak no more of
your rights to Casterly Rock.
Go.
One more thing.
The next whore I catch in your bed I'll hang.
SANSA: Dome. It's going to Dome.
SHAE: Why Dome?
It's carrying silk
and it's supposed to bring
back wine in exchange.
But it's not coming back.
The captain's tired of risking his life
so King's Landing lords and ladies
can get drunk
on better wine than they deserve.
He's going to stay in Dome.
Wait out the winter
where it's beautiful and warm.
I met some people in Dome
who weren't so beautiful and warm.
Don't ruin the game.
I told you. I don't want to play.
What about that one there?
SHAE: That one? It's going to Volantis.
Why?
Because when I got
on a ship in Volantis. it looked like that one.
That's not how the game works.
You're not supposed to just
blurt out the right answer.
You've got to invent a story about
Where the ship is going and why.
Why should I make up a story
when I know the truth?
Because the truth
is always either terrible or boring.
Lovely day for it.
Watching the ships.
Lord Baelish.
Might I speak
with Lady Sansa alone for a moment?
I saw your mother not long ago.
She's very eager to see you.
And your sister.
Arya's alive?
You said you'd take me home.
You said King's Landing was your home.
You are the property
of the crown. Stealing you would be treason.
If you were to tell just one person...
I won't tell anyone.
How do I know?
Because I'm a terrible liar.
You said so yourself.
Please. Lord Baelish.
Tell me what to do. Tell me when.
I'm waiting for word on an assignment
that will take me far away from the capital.
When I set sail.
I might be able to take you with me.
But you'll need to
be ready to leave on a moment's notice.
You're her handmaiden?
Yes. And you're his...
I help manage his affairs.
He's an important person.
So is she.
I grew up in the shadow of her father's castle.
The day she was born.
they rang the bells from sunrise till sunset.
We've both done rather well. you and I.
Yes.
Given where we started.
And where is that?
It's not easy
for girls like us to dig our way out.
Watch out for her.
I always do.
Watch out for her with him.
(DRAGON SCREECHING)
(ALL SCREECHING)
They're growing fast.
(PURRS)
Not fast enough.
I can't wait that long.
I need an army.
We'll be in Astapor by nightfall.
Some say the Unsullied
are the greatest soldiers in the world.
The greatest slave-soldiers in the world.
The distinction
means a good deal to some people.
Do those people have any better ideas
about how to put you on the Iron Throne?
It's too beautiful a day to argue.
(MAN VOMITING)
-You're right.
-(MAN COUGHING)
Another lovely day on the high seas.
DAENERYS: Don't mock them.
They're the first Dothraki on a ship.
They followed me across the poison water.
If they'll do it.
others will. And with a true khalasar...
The Dothraki follow strength
above all. Khaleesi.
You'll have a true
khalasar when you prove yourself strong.
And not before.
DAVOS: Your Grace.
I heard you were dead.
Not yet.
I had hoped to speak
to you alone. Your Grace.
We are alone.
Your Grace. you are the rightful king.
Not only by blood.
You're an honorable man. a just man.
And there is still a war to fight.
I am fighting.
By burning prisoners alive?
How would you punish
the infidels. Ser Davos?
I do not judge people
for the Gods they worship.
If I did. I'd have thrown you in the sea
before you ever set foot on Dragonstone.
I'm not your enemy.
You are my enemy.
Was it me you fought on Blackwater Bay?
Did I set your ships ablaze?
I wasn't there when the wildfire
killed our men by the thousands.
I could have saved those men.
You would have taken the city. Stannis would
sit upon his rightful throne.
and you would stand beside him.
But I wasn't there
because you convinced
your king to leave me behind.
Do you hear them screaming?
All those burning men
in the water crying for their mothers.
for their Gods for help?
Until the moment
the Blackwater swallowed them.
Don't despair. Ser Davos.
What I told your son is true.
Death by fire is the purest death.
(GRUNTS)
-This woman is evil!
-(KNIFE CLATTERING)
She's the mother of demons.
Take him and lock him in a cell.
-Your Grace!
-Come on.
You've chosen the darkness. Ser Davos.
She will destroy us all!
MELISANDRE: I will pray for you.
DAVOS: Your Grace!
(DOOR CLOSES)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
MAN 1: Halt. Down.
MAN 2: Halt. Down.
(THUDDING)
Why have we stopped?
It's Lady Margaery. Your Grace.
JOFFREY: What is she doing?
Who gave her permission?
FEMALE SERVANT: My lady.
We should have guards. my lady.
MARGAERY: Why?
Pardon me.
Stop. my lady. You'll ruin your dress.
I have others.
(BABY CRYING)
Would you like to speak with her. Your Grace?
(ALL MURMURING)
No.
He was a soldier.
He went to fight on the walls when the
ships came into Blackwater Bay.
He never came back.
And your mother?
She died when she had me.
Bad men wanted to
come into this city and do terrible things.
but your father stopped them.
Whenever you look at this knight.
I want you to remember your father.
He wasn't a knight. He was just a soldier.
And what do knights swear to do?
Protect the weak and uphold the good.
Your father did that. Be proud of him.
Was your father a soldier. too?
You should be proud. too.
Under King Joffrey's
leadership. your fathers saved the city.
They saved us all.
From now on. we're going to take care of you.
All of you.
-(CHILDREN CHATTERING EXCITEDLY)
{CHUCKLING)
Come to me for what you need to feed
them. clothe them. or house them.
Directly to me.
(MARGAERY CHUCKLING)
(DOOR OPENS)
-Your Grace.
Please. sit. Sit.
I do apologize. my lady.
Small Council meetings.
At what point does
it become treason to waste the king's time?
(CHUCKLES)
That's a lovely gown. my lady.
Yes. it suits you perfectly.
I imagine you might be rather cold.
The climate is a bit more forgiving
back in Highgarden. Your Grace.
JOFFREY: Shall I have them
bring you a shawl. my lady?
I am touched by your concern. Your Grace.
Luckily for us Tyrells.
our blood runs quite warm.
Doesn't it. Loras?
Yes.
Loras. isn't the queen's gown magnificent?
The fabric. the embroidery. the metalwork.
I've never seen anything like it.
You might find a bit of armor quite useful
once you become queen. Perhaps before.
Joffrey tells me you
stopped your carriage at Flea Bottom
on your way back from the sept this morning.
Yes. I paid a visit to an orphanage
the High Septon told me about.
Margaery does a great deal of work
with the poor back in Highgarden.
MARGAERY: The lowest
among us are no different from the highest
if you give them a chance
and approach them with an open heart.
CERSEI: An open heart is what you'll get
if you're not careful. my dear.
Not long ago.
we were attacked by a mob there.
We had a full complement
of guards that didn't stop them.
The king barely escaped with his life.
My mother's always had a penchant for drama.
Facts become less and
less important to her as she grows older.
Our lives were never truly in danger.
You're right. of course.
But you are your father's son.
We can't all have a king's bravery.
(SIGHS)
Hunger turns men into beasts.
I'm glad House Tyrell
has been able to help in this regard.
They tell me 100
wagons arrive daily now from the Reach.
Wheat. barley. apples.
We've had a blessed harvest.
And it's our duty
to assist the capital in time of need.
Well. as Ser Loras said.
Lady Margaery has done this sort
of. uh. charitable work before.
I'm sure she knows what she's doing.
I'm sure she does.
(DRAGONS SCREECHING)
(SPEAKS VALYRIAN)
MISSANDEI: The Unsullied have stood here
for a day and a night with no food or water.
(KRAZNYS CONTINUES
SPEAKING VALYRIAN)
MISSANDEI: They Will stand until they drop.
(KRAZNYS CONTINUES
SPEAKING VALYRIAN)
Such is their obedience.
They may suit my needs.
Tell me of their training.
(BOTH SPEAKING VALYRIAN)
The Westerosi woman is pleased with them.
but speaks no praise to keep the price down.
She wishes to know how they are trained.
Tell her what
she would know and be quick about it.
The day is hot.
MISSANDEI: They begin their training at 5.
Every day they drill from dawn to dusk
until they have mastered the shorts word.
the shield. and the three spears.
Only one boy in four
survives this rigorous training.
(SPEAKS VALYRIAN)
MISSANDEI: Their discipline
and loyalty are absolute.
They fear nothing.
Even the bravest men fear death.
(IN VALYRIAN)
The knight says even brave men fear death.
Tell the old man he smells of piss.
Truly. Master?
No. not truly.
Are you a girl or a goat to ask such a thing?
MISSANDEI: My master says the Unsullied
are not men. Death means nothing to them.
(IN VALYRIAN)
Tell this ignorant whore of a Westerner
to open her eyes and watch.
He begs you attend
to this carefully. Your Grace.
(SPEAKS VALYRIAN)
Tell the good master there is no need.
She's worried about their nipples?
Does the dumb bitch know
we've cut off their balls?
MISSANDEI: My master
points out that men don't need nipples.
(IN VALYRIAN)
Here. I'm done with you.
This one is pleased to have served you.
(KRAZNYS CONTINUES
SPEAKING VALYRIAN)
To win his shield.
an Unsullied must go
to the slave marts with a silver mark.
find a newborn
and kill it before its mother's eyes.
This way. my master says. we make certain
there is no weakness left in them.
You take a babe from its mother's arms.
kill it as she watches.
and pay for her pain with a silver coin?
(IN VALYRIAN)
She is offended.
She asks
if you pay a silver coin to the mother.
for her dead baby.
What a soft mewling fool this one is.
My master would
like you to know that the silver is paid
to the baby's owner. not the mother.
How many do you have to sell?
(MISSANDEI REPEATS IN VALYRIAN)
Eight thousand.
(IN VALYRIAN)
Tell the Westerosi whore
she has until tomorrow.
MISSANDEI: Master Kraznys
asks that you please hurry.
Many other buyers are interested.
DAENERYS: Eight thousand dead babies.
The Unsullied are a means to an end.
Once I own them. these men...
They're not men. Not anymore.
Once I own an army of slaves. what will I be?
You think these slaves will have better lives
serving men like Kraznys or serving you?
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
You'll be fair to them.
You won't mutilate them to make a point.
You won't order them to murder babies.
You'll see they're properly fed and sheltered.
A great injustice has been done to them.
Closing your eyes will not undo it.
(CHUCKLES)
(DAENERYS GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(HISSES)
The warlocks.
I owe you my life. ser.
The honor is mine. my queen.
You know this man?
I know him
as one of the greatest fighters
the Seven Kingdoms has ever seen
and as the Lord Commander
of Robert Baratheon's Kingsguard.
King Robert is dead.
I have been searching for you. Daenerys
Stormborn. to ask your forgiveness.
I was sworn to protect your family.
I failed them.
I am Barristan Selmy.
Kingsguard to your father.
Allow me to join your Queensguard
and I will not fail you again.